Guide to the Robert Alexander Papers 1962-1987 MSS 114
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series III: Negatives and Contact Sheets
  - Voices cover, 29 Oct 1978 (Box 36, Folder 44)
  - Whirling Dervishes, 30 Oct 1978 (Box 36, Folder 45)
  - Steve Paxton and David Moss, 31 Oct 1978 (Box 36, Folder 46)
  - The Theatre of Mistakes, 4 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 47)
  - Bruce McLean, 5 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 48)
  - Michael and Paul Galasso, 7 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 49)
  - Stephanie Woodard, 10 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 50)
  - Judy Nylon, 11 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 51)
  - Steve Paxton et al, Contact Improvisation, 11 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 52)
  - Naropa, Dancing Songs, 13 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 53)
  - Ann Cumming, 16 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 54)
  - Erik Roberts, 17 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 55)
  - Kipper Kids, 18 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 56)
  - San Francisco Mime Troupe, 19 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 57)
  - Bettany Beardsley, 20 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 58)
  - Dead Dog and Lonely Horse, 21 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 59)
  - Alvin Ailey, 22 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 60)
  - Tom Waits, 27 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 61)
  - Pooh Kaye, 30 Nov 1978 (Box 36, Folder 62)
  - Kenneth King, Carter Frank, Diane Jacobowitz, 8 Dec 1978 (Box 36, Folder 63)
  - Maple Sugar, 9 Dec 1978 (Box 36, Folder 64)
  - Geri Atwood, 12 Dec 1978 (Box 36, Folder 65)
  - Bill Dunas at The Kitchen, 12 Dec 1978 (Box 36, Folder 66)
  - Jill Kroesen at The Kitchen, 22 Dec 1978 (Box 36, Folder 67)
  - St Marks benefit, 1 Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Red Mole Theatre, Goin' to Djibouti, 14 Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Ron Robboy, 15 Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Jeff Goldblum, 19 Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Trisha Brown, 23 Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Meredith Monk, Vocal Music, 27 Jan 1979 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Deborah Hay rehearsal, 1 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Deborah Hay performance, 2 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Peter Boyle, 5 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Meredith Monk, Education of the Girlchild, 6 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Go-go dancer for Rudy Burckhardt film, 19 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Douglas Dunn rehearsal at Intermedia, 20 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Eleanor Antin, Before the Revolution, 24 Feb 1979 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Peter Ustinov, 1 Mar 1979 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Diane Jacobowitz, 4 Mar 1979 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Paul Zaloom, 10 Mar 1979 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Deborah Hay, The Grand Dance, 13 Mar 1979 (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Geri Atwood, 26 Mar 1979 (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - Ellen Webb, Dance Relaxation Techniques, 29 Mar 1979 (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - Yvonne Rainer, 1 Apr 1979 (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - Lucinda Childs, 11 Apr 1979 (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - Dean Selmier, 15 Apr 1979 (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - On Mount Chimborazo, 16 May 1979 (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - Hasidic wedding, June 1979 (Box 37, Folder 24)
  - Susan and Jen Yeh, 5 Aug 1979 (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - Kate Yeh, 19 Aug 1979 (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - Diane Jacobowitz, 12 Sep 1979 (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - Laura Foreman, Hisachika Takahashi, John Watts, 13 Sep 1979 (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - Headshots (Rachel?), 9 Nov 1979 (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - Sheeler photos for Susan Yeh, 14 Dec 1979 (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - Shiatsu hands, 15 Dec 1979 (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - Laura Foreman, 22 Jan 1980 (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - Yoshiko Chuma, 9 Mar 1980 (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - Pooh Kaye and co., 10 Mar 1980 (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - Jane Stevens, Blue installation, 30 Apr 1980 (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - Lab glass, 13 May 1980 (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - Diane Jacobowitz, 2 June 1980 (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - Liz Ross, 4 June 1980 (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - Julie Cole (nudes) 15 July 1980 (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - Commercial work - tile brochure, 22 July 1980 (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - Commercial work - Mitsubishi, 4 Aug 1980 (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - Alex Katz mural - Attorney General's office, 18 Sep 1980 (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - Min Tanaka, 14 Nov 1980 (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - Commercial work - Baker assembly plant, 19 Nov 1980 (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - Carter Frank and son, 29 Nov 1980 (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - Andrea Levine, n/d, undated (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - Christmas party at garment center, 17 Dec 1980 (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - Andrea Levine, [1982], undated (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - Shelley at Ear Inn, Feb 1982 (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - Denman, 28 Feb 1982 (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - Street scenes, NYC, 1982 (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - Netherlands Dance Theater, 13 July 1982 (Box 37, Folder 52)
  - Personal - Ann Beckerman, Brighton Beach, July 1982 (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - Various - self portraits, street scenes, etc, Aug 1982 (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - Various personal, [Oct 1982], undated (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - American Ballet Theater gala (Raul Julia, Natalia Makarova, et al), 16 Oct 1982 (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - Personal - domestic still life, Dec 1982 (Box 37, Folder 57)
  - Various - self portraits, Ann Beckerman, NYC, domestic, Apr/June 1983 (Box 37, Folder 58)
  - Julie Finch and Lynn Walker, 8 May 1983 (Box 37, Folder 59)
  - Merce Cunningham at Park Avenue Armory, June 1983 (Box 37, Folder 60)
  - Yoshiko Chuma rehearsal at The Kitchen, 8 Dec 1983 (Box 37, Folder 61)
  - Building, n/d, undated (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - Lab chimpanzees for the NYU Physician (see prints, box 6), Spring 1984 (Box 37, Folder 63)
  - Various - personal, May 1986 (Box 37, Folder 64)
  - Various - city, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 65)
  - Various - city, buildings, 1986 (Box 37, Folder 66)
  - Central Park, Ann Beckerman, n/d, undated (Box 37, Folder 67)
  - Various - Robert Alexander, Ann Beckerman, streets, forest, lawn chairs, n/d, undated (Box 37, Folder 68)
- Series IV: Printed and other materials
  - Subseries A: Printed material, memorabilia, correspondence, ephemera
    - Pilgrimage certificate, marriage certificate and photo., undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Letters and postcards, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Letters to Robert Alexander from Kenneth King and Martha Graham., undated (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Letters to Robert Alexander from Simone Forti and Peter Van Riper, Simone Forti, Lucinda Childs, Trisha Brown, Artist Housing for New York City., undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Letters to Robert Alexander from Kenneth King, Deborah Hay, Denman, Rob and Nancy., undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Letters from Robert Alexander to Sally Banes, Judy O'Gorman, Karen, Enrico, Lindsay Audin, Barrett Gallagher nominating Peter Moore for Performing Arts Photography Award 1982. (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Letter from Robert Alexander to Flower Tenants Corporation., undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Notes, cards, ephemera., undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Diary 1982, address book., undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
    - Personal notebook/journal., undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Personal diary/notebook., undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
    - Personal diaries/notebooks (2)., undated (Box 38, Folder 12)
    - Personal letters and accounts of dreams., undated (Box 38, Folder 13)
    - Various personal photos, slides, polaroids (family etc)., undated (Box 38, Folder 14)
    - Divorce papers, last will and testament., undated (Box 38, Folder 15)
    - Documents pertaining to Flower Tenants Corporation., undated (Box 38, Folder 16)
    - Resumes, undated (Box 38, Folder 17)
    - Parsons, Summer 1979. (Box 38, Folder 18)
    - Invoices 1975. (Box 38, Folder 19)
    - Invoices 1976. (Box 38, Folder 20)
    - Invoices 1977. (Box 38, Folder 21)
    - Invoices 1978. (Box 38, Folder 22)
    - Invoices 1979. (Box 38, Folder 23)
    - Invoices 1980. (Box 38, Folder 24)
    - Invoices 1981. (Box 38, Folder 25)
    - Invoices 1982. (Box 38, Folder 26)
    - Income and expenses ledger, 1981, 1982. (Box 38, Folder 27)
    - Playbills., undated (Box 38, Folder 28)
    - Ads, flyers, posters, programs for various performances., undated (Box 38, Folder 29)
    - Advertising for various performances: Julie Finch et al, Geri Atwood, Grand Union., undated (Box 38, Folder 30)
    - Poster for Carter Frank and Geri Atwood Dance Solos and Duet., undated (Box 38, Folder 31)
    - Documents, clippings, projects., undated (Box 38, Folder 32)
    - Cuttings etc on career workshops (with Henrietta Brackman)., undated (Box 38, Folder 33)
    - Memorabilia/ads for Alternative Gestures exhibition at P.S. 1, Dec 1978 - Jan 1979. (Box 38, Folder 34)
    - Manuscript of Cops, play by Terry Curtis Fox., undated (Box 38, Folder 35)
    - Sheldon Frank manuscript., undated (Box 38, Folder 36)
    - Arnie Klein manuscript., undated (Box 38, Folder 37)
    - Soho Weekly News tear sheets, 16 March 1978 - 31 January 1980. (Box 38, Folder 38)
    - Layout notes for Terpsichore in Sneakers., undated (Box 38, Folder 39)
    - Letters and documents pertaining to Terpsichore in Sneakers, undated (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - Oversize - Subseries A
    - Record covers, tear sheets from Life magazine (Jan 1983) and Footwear News magazine., undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
    - Memorabilia from Alternative Gestures show at P.S. 1, Dec 1978 - Jan 1979. (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Poster: "Harry Schwartz Moved His Studio "., undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Dance posters: Kenneth King, Camptown(Pooh Kaye et al), Ragged Valley(Yoshiko Chuma)., undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Proofs for cover of Terpsichore in Sneakers., undated (Box 39, Folder 5)
- Series V: Motion Picture Film Material
  This series consists of original motion picture film elements. Access copies may not be available for consultation. Please see Series VI: Videotape Recordings, Subseries A: Access Copies for film-to-tape transfers, or consult a Fales archivist.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Access
    Please see available film-to-tape transfers in Series VI: Videotape Recordings, Subseries A: Access Copies, or ask a Fales archivist.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    Researcher use is limited to Subseries A: Access Copies. Please consult a Fales Archivist for assistance.
    - [New York City Streetscape], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0001)
      Physical Characterisitcs and Technical Requirements note
      Format: Super 8 film
      Length: 50-ft reel
      Brand: Kodachrome
    - [New York City Streetscape, Indoor Telephone Shot], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0002)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
    - [People by Poolside], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0003)
    - [People, Trucks on Street], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0004)
      Length: 50-ft. reels
    - [Plastic Bag], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0005)
    - [Street Scene, Skylight], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0006)
      Physical Characterstics and Technical Requirements note
    - Corner Walking, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0007 - 114.0009)
      Length: 3, 50-ft. reels
      Brand: Ektachrome
    - Panoramic Hotel, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0010)
      Lenght: 1, 50-ft. reel
    - By the Pool, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0011 - 114.0014)
      Length: 4, 50-ft. reels
    - Approach to Montauk, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0015)
      Length: 1, 50-ft. reel
    - Montauk, Rock and Stuff, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0016)
    - Toshi, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0017)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirement note
      Length: 1 50-ft. reel
    - Bean-Mother Outtakes, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0018 - 114.0022)
      Length: 5, 50-ft reels, numbered sequentially
    - Kite on Beach, Driving to Montauk, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0023)
      Length: Kodachrome
    - Venetian Blinds, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0024)
      Length: 1, 50-ft reel, original
      Brand: [no film stock information]
    - Jawbone, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0025)
    - Baudelaire's Mother, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0026)
      Length: 1 reel (approx. 75 ft.), edited original
    - Summer Garden K.K. [Kenneth King], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0027 - 114.0028)
      Length: 2, 50-ft. rolls, original
    - Carter F[rank] Dancing, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0029)
      Length: 1, 50-ft. roll, original
    - First Roll, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0030)
      Length: 50-ft. roll
    - Second Roll, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0031)
    - [Untitled], undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0032 - 114.0038)
      Length: 7, 50-ft. reels, original
    - Ann on Ladder, undated (Box 40, Media ID: 114.0039)
      Physical Chartacteristics and Technical Requirements note
      Format: 16mm film
      Length: [unknown]
      Brand: [unknown]
    - Trio A, Yvonne Rainer - performer, choreographer; Robert Alexander, camera, 1978 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 114.0040)
      Format: 16mm
- Series VI: Videotape Recordings
  This series consists of film-to-video transfers of original film material found in Series V. Please contact a Fales archivist for assistance.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Conditions Governing Acess
    Please consult a Fales archivist for assistance.
    - Baudelaire's Mother, October 1977 (Shelf Media, Media ID: 114.0055)
      General note
      Format: DVD
      Duration: 00:04:10
      Original Format: Super 8mm Film
    - Carter Frank Dancing, undated (Shelf Media, Media ID: 114.0057)
      Duration: 00:03:25
- Series VII: Sound Recordings
  This series consists of original sound recordings. Access copies are not currently available for consultation. Please contact a Fales archivist for assistance.
  - Subseries A: Access Copies
    Access copies are not currently available for consultation. Please contact a Fales archivist for assistance.
  - Subseries B: Originals
    Please consult a Fales Archivist for assistance.
    - Audio cassette - "Journal 71-73," 1 30-minute Sony tape, 1971 - 1973 (Box 41, Media ID: 114.0046)
    - Audio cassette - "For you" and "Plumbing Music," Peter Van Riper, Nov. 1977 performance, St. Marks, 1 60-minute Basf tape (Box 41, Media ID: 114.0047)
    - Audio cassette - "Solo for Body and Clocks," tapes 1-3, April 30, 1977 performance Alternate Space Gallery, 1 worktape, all TDK 60-minute tapes (Box 41, Media ID: 114.0048 - 114.0051)
    - Audio cassette - "Henrietta Brackman," 4 90-minute Ampex tapes, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 114.0042 - 114.0045)
    - Audio cassette - 1 unlabelled 90-minute tape, undated (Box 41, Media ID: 114.0041)